Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Two girls in light colored gowns sitting on furniture. 16.2 x 10.6 cm, Undated; 3538; Studio Photo L'Aigle, Grand Rue de Pera 429, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Children; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Girls; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Group Portraits
- Soldier with mustache in uniform and hat. 23.6 x 16.1 cm, Undated; 3539; Studio Photo L'Aigle, Grand Rue de Pera 429, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Uniforms; Facial Hair; Hats; Military/Soldiers
- Two men in coats and hats, one man lighting his cigarette from the other's. 7.8 x 4.6 cm, Circa 1888-1910; 3540; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Umbrellas/Parasols; Gloves; Canes/Walking Sticks; Constantinople; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Smoking; Cigarettes; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Hats; Facial Hair; Group Portraits
- Adele and Therese Honegger as young girls, in white gowns sitting on a chair. Therese Honegger also appears in ref8 and ref69. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Circa 1868; 3550; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  French Writing; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Children; Girls; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
- Arman Hisaryan as a boy standing, leaning against a table with a book in his hand. 10.6 x 6.5 cm, Undated; 3552; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Books; Painted Backdrops; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Children; Constantinople; Boys; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Man standing with walking stick. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated; 3553; Studio G. Wunsch, Vienna, Austria (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Facial Hair; Turkish Writing; Studio Photography; Armenian Writing; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Carpets/Rugs; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Vienna, Austria; Austria; Men; Facial Hair
- Portrait of Crown Prince Mozaffar ad-Din (1853-1907), son of Naser al-Din Shah Qajar (1831-1896). 10.3 x 6.5 cm, Undated; 3554; Studio Window & Grove, London, England (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; London, England, UK; Fezes/Tarbouches; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; English Writing; Studio Photography; Hats; Facial Hair
- Portrait of Naser al-Din Shah Qajar (1831-1896) 10.3 x 6.5 cm, Undated; 3555; Studio Window & Grove, London, England (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Facial Hair; London, England, UK; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Men; Fur Garments; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches
- Portrait of Ottoman General Omer Pasha (Michael Lattas, 1801-1871). 10.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated; 3556; Studio L. Angerer, Vienna, Austria (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Weapons; Military/Soldiers; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair; English Writing; Vienna, Austria; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Swords/Knives; Uniforms; Pasha; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Portrait of Muhammad III as-Sadiq (1813-1882), ruler of Tunisia from 1859-1881. Same subject as ref58. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated; 3557; Studio Disderi, 8 Boulevard des Italiens (Paris, France) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Tunisia; Facial Hair; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Paris, France; English Writing; Men; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Standing portrait of Muhammad III as-Sadiq (1813-1882), leader of Tunisia from 1859-1881. Same subject as ref57. 10.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated; 3558; Studio Disderi, 8 Boulevard des Italiens (Paris, France) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Tunisia; Facial Hair; Paris, France; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Furnishings; Facial Hair; Men
- Portrait of man with mustache. 10.7 x 6.6 cm, Undated; 3559; Studio Carlo Bukmedjian, Rue des Roses 7, Izmir (Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Izmir, Turkey; Smyrna; Albumen Prints; Men; Facial Hair
- Man with mustache and beard sitting on a chair. 10.3 x 6.1cm, Circa 1865; 3560; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Men; Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair
- Man with mustache sitting on chair, leaning on elbow on a table. 10 x 6.2 cm, Circa 1865; 3561; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Men; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- Andon Hisaryan standing with a book in his hand, leaning on an upholstered chair. Name written on back in pencil. 10.6 x 6.5 cm, Undated; 3562; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Constantinople; Men; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Books; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Woman in glasses, holding a white cloth, sitting next to a table with books. Identical to ref79. 11 x 6.7 cm, Undated; 3563; Studio Basile Kargopoulo Photographe, Place du Tunnel No. 4, Pera, Constantinople (Succursale à Andrinople (Edirne)) (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Books; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Women; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Studio Photography
- Seyyid Abdulkadir (1851-1925), Kurdish rebel leader. 10 x 6.3 cm, Undated; 3567; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Books; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople; Furnishings; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Ottoman Writing; Studio Photography
- Sura-yi Devlet azasi (member of the state council) Muhsin Bey. 10.6 x 6.4 cm, 10 April 1888; 3571; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Men; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Cairo, Egypt; Facial Hair; Turkish Writing; Ottoman Writing; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints
- Dr. Ali Haydar Bey (1880-1923). 10.4 x 6.1 cm, 1865; 3574; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Turkish Writing; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Fur Garments; Umbrellas/Parasols; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Doctors; Men; Constantinople; Ottoman Writing
- William Gottlieb Schanffler (August 22, 1798 – January 27, 1883), German missionary, and his wife Mary R. Schanffler (Reynolds). Names written on front. 10.4 x 6.3 cm, Circa 1868; 3575; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Men; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Women; Group Portraits
- Vezir Mehmed Memduh Pasa (1839-1925), statesman, writer, poet. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated; 3578; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Pens/Inkwells; Furnishings; Books; Poetry; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing; Ottoman Writing; Constantinople; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Men; Facial Hair
- Therese Honegger as a young girl. Subject also in ref51 and ref8. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, 1869; 3580; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Studio Photography; Children; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Religious Crosses; Constantinople; Individual Portraits; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey
- Portrait of an Ottoman Prince. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, 1873; 3585; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Children; Hats; Boys; Fezes/Tarbouches; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Furnishings; Constantinople; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography
- Girl standing on chair, leaning on pillow. 10.4 x 6.3 cm, 1882; 3586; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Children; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Constantinople; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Woman standing in a light-colored dress with dark lace trim. 10.5 x 6.2 cm, 1860; 3587; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Constantinople; Women; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Furnishings
- Man with mustache wearing a fez and patterned tie. 14.1 x 10.6 cm, 1912-1913; 3589; Osmanli Fotografhanesi, Skopje (Macedonia) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Skopje, Macedonia; Men; Ottoman Writing; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Hats; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Portrait of Miss Laura Farnham (1844-1919), principal of a school in Adapazari, Turkey. 14.3 x 9.7 cm, Undated; 3594; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Embroidery; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; English Writing; Teachers; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints
- Man in three-piece suit with goatee beard. 10.3 x 6.1 cm, Undated; 3595; Studio B. Kargopoulo & Foscolo, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Constantinople; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Men; Facial Hair
- Woman in lace trimmed dress, holding a hand fan, sitting on chair. 10.5 x 6.4 cm, Undated; 3596; Studio Basile Kargopoulo Photographe, Place du Tunnel No. 4, Pera, Constantinople (Succursale à Andrinople (Edirne)) (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Constantinople; Furnishings; Hand Fans; Albumen Prints
- Yegane Hanim. 10.1 x 6.2 cm, 1860; 3597; Studio Basile Kargopoulo Photographe, Place du Tunnel No. 4, Pera, Constantinople (Succursale à Andrinople (Edirne)) (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Jewelry; Books; Furnishings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Women; Ottoman Writing; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople
- Man with side whiskers style beard in dark coat. 10.9 x 6.6 cm, Undated; 3598; Studio Basile Kargopoulo Photographe, Place du Tunnel No. 4, Pera, Constantinople (Succursale à Andrinople (Edirne)) (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Men; Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey
- Woman in glasses, holding a white cloth, sitting next to a table with books. Identical to ref63. 11 x 6.7 cm, Undated; 3607; Studio Basile Kargopoulo Photographe, Place du Tunnel No. 4, Pera, Constantinople (Succursale à Andrinople (Edirne)) (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Books; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops
- Man with a mustache wearing a fez, holding a book. 16.9 x 11.3 cm, Undated; 3608; Studio Basile Kargopoulo Photographe, Place du Tunnel No. 4, Pera, Constantinople (Succursale à Andrinople (Edirne)) (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Jewelry; Books; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Men; Facial Hair
- Standing man in uniform, holding gloves and a walking stick. Possibly Dr. Kirimli Aziz Bey (1840-1878). 16.6 x 10.7 cm, Undated; 3609; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Uniforms; Doctors; Gloves; Canes/Walking Sticks; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Painted Backdrops; Turkish Writing; Furnishings; Ottoman Writing; Men; Photographic Prints
- Soldier with a sword and gloves. 16.5 x 10.7 cm, 1884; 3610; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Individual Portraits; Hats; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Gloves; Fezes/Tarbouches; Embroidery; Books; Medals/Insignia; Furnishings; Men; Swords/Knives; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Weapons
- Man with fez and mustache with a medal pinned to his chest. 16.4 x 10.9 cm, Undated; 3611; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Medals/Insignia
- Man with large mustache in a dark coat. 16.6 x 10.6 cm, Undated; 3612; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Bow Ties; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair
- Portrait of Caroline Livadari. 10.1 x 6.2 cm, 1875; 3613; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Religious Crosses; Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewelry
- Man with mustache, wearing fez, standing with hand on chair. Numbers written on front. 10.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated; 3614; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Furnishings; Men; French Writing
- Suleymaniye Mosque. 18.8 x 17.1 cm, Undated; 3615; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Buildings; Istanbul, Turkey; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; Suleymaniye Mosque; Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Bridges
- Uchisar and Uchisar Castle, Cappadocia. 18.1 x 23.9 cm, Circa 1950; 3616; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Istanbul, Turkey; Uchisar, Cappadocia; Architecture; Houses; Landscapes; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Karkamis Iron Bridge (1917) passing over the Euphrates river in Karkamis, Turkey and a camel. 17.9 x 24.4 cm, Undated; 3617; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Camels; Bridges; Gelatin Silver Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Animals; Landscapes; German Writing; Euphrates River
- Rumelihisari Castle. 23.8 x 18 cm, Undated; 3618; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Military/Soldiers; Architecture; Snow; Istanbul, Turkey; Rumelihisari, Istanbul, Turkey
- Man with white beard and a white turban, kneeling next to a mosque window, reading the Quran. 23.8 x 18.2 cm, Undated; 3629; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Mosques; Gelatin Silver Prints; Carpets/Rugs; Hats; Praying; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Men; Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair
- Sultan Ahmed Mosque, street seller in the snow. 18.1 x 23.9 cm, Circa 1930; 3630; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Streets/Roads; Buildings; Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites; Men; Snow; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Individual Portraits
- Tombstones in Ahlat, Turkey. 23.8 x 16.1 cm, Undated; 3631; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Tombs; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Religious Sites; Ahlat, Turkey
- Light fixtures, arches and windows in the interior of Suleymaniye Mosque. 23.8 x 18.2 cm, Undated; 3633; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Religious Sites; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Carpets/Rugs; Architecture; Suleymaniye Mosque; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Interior of dome in Suleymaniye Mosque. 23.9 x 18.1 cm, Undated; 3635; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Suleymaniye Mosque; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
- Wall of windows and mihrab with men praying in the Blue Mosque in Istanbul, Turkey. 23.8 x 18.1 cm, Undated; 3639; Othmar, Pferschy (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Religious Sites; Istanbul, Turkey; Carpets/Rugs; Praying; Men; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Photographic Prints
- Boy in a sailor suit leaning on a studio prop boulder. 16.1 x 10.5 cm, Circa 1895; 3640; Studio Parnasse, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Children; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Books; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Hats; Bow Ties; Boys; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Maritime/Nautical Outfits
- Haldun. "Souvenir to my dear aunt" 16.1 x 10.5 cm, 31 December 1902; 3641; Studio Parnasse, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople; Children; Ottoman Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Books; Boys
- Boy with high white collar and a flower in his lapel. 16.5 x 10.7 cm, Undated; 3642; Studio Parnasse, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Boys; Children; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Albumen Prints
- Muhammed Sabri and Selahaddin. Two young men signed the photograph as a gift to their aunt. 23.9 x 17 cm, 1899; 3643; Studio Parnasse, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder Oversize)
  Men; Books; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Ottoman Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Woman in dark dress with pin on collar. 16.6 x 10.7 cm, 25 December; 3651; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  English Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Jewelry; Women
- Woman in hat with a bow on her collar holding a baby in a gown. (French writing on the back, "The blessed child of the Arzuman family 1905"). 18.7 x 13.7 cm, 3653; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Children; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Hats; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Women; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey
- Albanian Girl. 20.8 x 13.5 cm, 1890; 3654; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Women; Albumen Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Turkish Writing; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Embroidery; Pottery
- Man and a woman standing in a wedding dress. Kemaciyan. 21.7 x 13.2 cm, Undated; 3655; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Weddings; Weddings; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Weddings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Gloves; Carpets/Rugs; Constantinople
- Man with beard wearing a fez and a dark coat sitting in a chair. Same subject as ref106. 21.4 x 13.5 cm, 1880s; 3657; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Men
- Man with beard in a white suit, dark coat and a fez, sitting on a chair. Same subject as ref105. 21.5 x 13.8 cm, 1888; 3659; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Books; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Men; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats
- Soldiers with binoculars around their necks sitting on horses. 19.1 x 24.2 cm, 6 November 1918; 3665; Pokoriya, Odessa (Ukraine) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Ottoman Writing; Odessa, Ukraine; Binoculars; Men; Flags; Group Portraits; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Horses; Military/Soldiers; Outdoors; Animals; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Uniforms
- A porter surrounded by street dogs. 25.9 x 18.6 cm, Circa 1880; 3666; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Animals; Facial Hair; Outdoors; Facial Hair; Doors/Entrances; Streets/Roads; French Writing; Hats; Food; Cigarettes; Dogs; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Individual Portraits
- Two men in suits and two women wearing dresses and pearls with a small boy. 28.9 x 19.8 cm, 14 February 1930; 3667; Unknown (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Turkish Writing; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Jewelry; Children; Boys; Women; Men; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair